Guide to the Ulysses S. Grant Foundation Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Ulysses S. Grant Foundation records
1965-1995
RU 895
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
The records consist of annual reports, proposals, correspondence, and meeting minutes maintained by James R. Vivian, chairman of the Ulysses S. Grant Foundation board of directors.
Ulysses S. Grant Foundation
Vivian, James R.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 37 (YRG 37), Records of associations, institutes, centers, and organizations affiliated with Yale.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by record type.
Biographical / Historical
The Ulysses S. Grant Foundation is an educational enrichment program for academically talented and motivated middle school students from New Haven, Connecticut. The program is designed to prepare students with limited opportunities and resources for entry and success in college.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of annual reports, proposals, correspondence, and meeting minutes maintained by James R. Vivian, chairman of the Ulysses S. Grant Foundation board of directors.
Developmental studies programs; Education; Ulysses S. Grant Foundation
- Records of James Vivian as chairman of the board of directors, circa 1965-1995; Accession 2002-A-104
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2030
  - Yale Charities Drive (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Yale Grant (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Yale College Word / Study Funds (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Students (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Former Grant Faculty and Staff (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Grant Staff Housing (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School and College Placement (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Placement and Follow - up (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proposal Draft by James Winn (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Proposal Draft by George Davis (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Proposal Draft by Marian Borden (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - US Grant Position Description (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Position Descriptions (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - New Haven Foundation Grant, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - New Haven Foundation Proposal, 1980 June 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Grant Literature and Publicity (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Evaluation by Mason Lowance, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Evaluation by Mason Lowance, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Hughes Grant (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Evaluation Forms (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Staff (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - English Dept. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Curriculum (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Conntac (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Community Development Grant (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Classroom Space (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - IRS Form for Grant (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Fact Sheets (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Bylaws (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Love of Teaching fuels Weekly Bulletin, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Editorial: Grant lacks Ethnic Perspective, 1990 September (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Financial (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Faculty Handbook (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Budgets (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Board Minutes (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Board Members (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Annual Report, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Annual Report, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Admissions, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Academic Committee (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Memos, Reminders Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Academic Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Endowment, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Proposal Number 15 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Annual Report
    - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - 1981 (Box 2, Folder 59 - 60)
  - High Speed U.S. Grant Literary Magazine, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Annual Report, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 62 - 63)
  - Magazine / Yale Daily News Magazine, 1983 September (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Annual Report
    - 1983 (Box 2, Folder 66 - 68)
    - 1984 (Box 2, Folder 69 - 71)
  - A Study of The Ulysses S. Grant Foundation by L. Scott Lerner and Julie Williams, 1984 April 2 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Annual Report
    - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - 1986 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - 1988 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Summer Report, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - The Director's Book (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Annual Report, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Literary Magazine Summer, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Annual Report
    - 1992 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - 1993 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - 1994 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 83)